<rss version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[ Journal of Lightwave Technology - new TOC ]]></title><link/> http://ieeexplore.ieee.org<description>出版物 TOC 提醒# 50</description><year> 2023年</year><month>七月</month><day>06 </day><item><title><![CDATA[Front Cover]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10171125]]><description><![CDATA[ ]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10171125]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> C1</startpage><endpage> C1</endpage><filesize> 185 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[ ]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Journal of Lightwave Technology Publication Information]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10171120]]><description><![CDATA[ ]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10171120]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> C2</startpage><endpage> C2</endpage><filesize> 104 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[ ]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Table of Contents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10164794]]><description><![CDATA[ ]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10164794]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3649</startpage><endpage> 3651</endpage><filesize> 155 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[ ]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[100 Gbit/s PAM-4 Linear Burst-Mode Transimpedance Amplifier for Upstream Flexible Passive Optical Networks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10083321]]><description><![CDATA[Next-generation passive optical networks (PONs) with upstream rates of 50 Gbit/s and beyond will require a new class of burst-mode transimpedance amplifiers (BMTIAs) that are linear to enable (digital) equalization of channel impairments. Such linear BMTIAs also enable higher-order modulation formats like 4-level pulse amplitude modulation (PAM-4). In this paper, we demonstrate operation of a novel linear BMTIA integrated together with a commercial off-the-shelf 25G-class avalanche photodiode (APD), achieving 50 Gbit/s non-return-to-zero (NRZ) operation with a sensitivity of &#x2212;23.7 dBm optical modulation amplitude (OMA) and dynamic range exceeding 21.7 dB and 100 Gbit/s PAM-4 operation with a sensitivity of &#x2212;15.8 dBm OMA and dynamic range exceeding 15.4 dB, both at a bit error ratio (BER) of <inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX">$10^{-2}$</tex-math></inline-formula> 。此外，快速突发模式增益控制和平衡电路将交流耦合电路情况下的强弱灵敏度损失限制在 1.3 dB 以下。该芯片采用 0.13 设计<inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX">$亩$</tex-math></inline-formula> m SiGe:C BiCMOS 技术，面积为 1.2 × 1.7 mm<inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX"> $^{2}$</tex-math></inline-formula>功耗在 260 mW 至 310 mW 之间。该接收器为下一代 BMTIA 铺平了道路，支持 ITU-T G.9804.3 Amd 1 标准。]]>; </description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10083321]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3652</startpage><endpage> 3659</endpage><filesize> 2966 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Gertjan Coudyzer;Michiel Verplaetse;Borre Van Lombergen;Robert Borkowski;Thibaut Gurne;Michael Straub;Yannick Lefevre;Peter Ossieur;René Bonk;Werner Coomans;Jochen Maes;Xin Yin;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Field Trial of SDN-Controlled Probabilistic Constellation Shaping Supporting Multiple Rates Over a Coupled-Core Multi-Core Fiber]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10093924]]><description><![CDATA[Space division multiplexing (SDM) is being investigated in support of traffic growth. SDM networks offer multiplexing over space and spectrum dimensions. Probabilistic constellation shaping (PCS) is a solution to optimize spectral efficiency by adapting the constellation of a M-ary quadrature amplitude modulated (QAM) signal to physical layer impairments. At the control plane, in the recent years NETCONF and YANG have been identified as the protocol and the data modeling language, respectively, for the configuration and management of network devices. Significant effort has also been directed to network disaggregation and vendor neutrality: an example is the work done within the OpenConfig consortium. In this article, we present a SDM field trial based on a deployed coupled-core four-core fiber, where a software-defined network (SDN) controller configures probabilistic constellation shaping through NETCONF, by optimizing spectral efficiency either with respect to the path length, or in response to degradations due to soft failures. The NETCONF protocol relies on the OpenConfig YANG data model to configure and manage transceivers. In the field trial the integrated data and control planes are demonstrated with multiple rates (800-850-900-950-1000 Gb&#x002F;s) for optical reach values ranging from 910 km to 2730 km. Soft failures are also introduced and a characterization of their impact on transmission performance is provided in order to design the recovery strategy deployed by SDN controller. Indeed, depending on the changes in the electrical signal-to-noise ratio, the SDN controller reconfigures the constellation shaping to restore the optical connection affected by the failure with a reduced line rate.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10093924]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3660</startpage><endpage> 3667</endpage><filesize> 2183 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[N. Sambo;A. Nespola;A. Sgambelluri;A. Marotta;L. Dallachiesa;R. Ryf;P. Castoldi;A. Mecozzi;T. Hayashi;A. Carena;C. Antonelli;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Demonstration and Characterization of High-Throughput 200.5 Tbit&#x002F;s S&#x002B;C&#x002B;L Transmission over 2x100 PSCF Spans]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10101790]]><description><![CDATA[Recent advances in multi-band amplification support ultra-wideband (UWB) systems as a suitable solution to cope with the increasing fiber communications traffic demand. The combination of UWB with spectral-efficient modulation formats can significantly increase in the total throughput of wavelength division multiplexed (WDM) transmission systems. In this work, we demonstrate a 240&#x00D7;70 Gbaud PCS-256QAM WDM transmission using an optical bandwidth of 150 nm across the S, C and L bands. We combine doped-fiber amplifiers, semiconductor optical amplifiers (SOA) and backward distributed Raman amplification to achieve 200.5 Tbit&#x002F;s of total generalized mutual information (GMI) throughput over two 100 km pure-silica-core fibers (PSCFs). We also present the digital twin of this experiment, providing the impact of wavelength-dependent impairments on the system performance. Our results demonstrate the feasibility of high-throughput multi-span UWB transmission.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10101790]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3668</startpage><endpage> 3673</endpage><filesize>第1182章</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Salma Escobar-Landero;Xiaohui Zhao;Dylan Le Gac;Abel Lorences-Riesgo;Tugdual Viret-Denaix;Qiang Guo;Lin Gan;Shujie Li;Shiyi Cao;Xinhua Xiao;Iosif Demirtzioglou;Nayla El Dahdah;Antonin Gallet;Shuqi Yu;Hartmut Hafermann;Loig Godard;Romain Brenot;Yann Frignac;Gabriel Charlet;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[260-GBaud Single-Wavelength Coherent Transmission Over 100-km SSMF Based on Novel Arbitrary Waveform Generator and Thin-Film Niobate I&#x002F;Q Modulator]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10109092]]><description><![CDATA[In this paper, we demonstrate up to 260-GBaud single-wavelength coherent transmission by employing an optical transmitter based on two wide-bandwidth devices: a novel 260-GS&#x002F;s arbitrary waveform generator with a 10-dB bandwidth of 90-GHz and a thin-film Lithium Niobate I&#x002F;Q modulator with a 3-dB bandwidth of 110-GHz. We first assess the performance of our high symbol rate transmitter for generating spectrally efficient Nyquist multilevel modulation format signals at symbol rates up to 210-GBaud with >;1.4-Tbps achievable information rates and by using linear digital signal processing only. We achieve up to 1.84-Tbps at 185-GBaud using PCS-64QAM, highlighting the linear behavior of our transmitter for high symbol rate Nyquist signaling. We then switch to dual-polarization QPSK coherent transmission and further increase the symbol rate up to 260-GBaud. Without using nonlinear digital-signal-processing nor advanced inter-symbol-interference mitigation techniques, we successfully transmit 260-GBaud QPSK at 800-Gbps net rate over 100-km of standard single mode fiber.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10109092]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3674</startpage><endpage> 3679</endpage><filesize> 1510 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Sylvain Almonacil;Haik Mardoyan;Filipe Jorge;Fabio Pittalà;Mengyue Xu;Benjamin Krueger;Fabrice Blache;Bernadette Duval;Lifeng Chen;Yangjie Yan;Xiaoyan Ye;Amirhossein Ghazisaeidi;Sina Rimpf;Yuntao Zhu;Jy Wang;Michel Goix;Ziyang Hu;Margaux Duthoit;Markus Gruen;Xinlun Cai;Jeremie Renaudier;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Silicon Photonic Phase-Diverse Receiver Enabling Transmission of >;Net 250 Gbps&#x002F;&#x03BB; Over 40 km for High-Speed and Low-Cost Short-Reach Optical Communications]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10113159]]><description><![CDATA[The fast growth of data traffic in short-reach optical communications drives the demand for high-speed and low-cost optical modules. Here we demonstrate a silicon photonic (SiP) phase-diverse receiver based on our recently proposed asymmetric self-coherent detection (ASCD) scheme with Mach-Zehnder interferometers (MZI). The SiP MZI-ASCD receiver has a hardware-efficient architecture and recovers complex double-sideband signals via the beatings between a signal portion and a delayed signal portion from an asymmetric MZI using only 2 single-ended photodiodes and 2 analog-to-digital converters. The removal of the local oscillator in the direct detection receiver enables low-cost uncooled lasers, whereas the phase diversity closes the gap with coherent detection in terms of electrical spectral efficiency (ESE). Using a SiP MZI-ASCD receiver with a 15 ps delay, we detect a 60 Gbaud single-polarization 16-QAM signal transmitted over 40 km of single-mode fiber (SMF) below 20&#x0025; overhead (OH) SD-FEC threshold of 2 &#x00D7; 10<sup> −2，净比特率为 200 Gbps，每偏振每波长的记录净 ESE 为 5.86 b/s/Hz。使用具有 7.5 ps 不同延迟的 SiP MZI-ASCD 接收器，可在 4.5 × 10 <sup>-2</sup>的 24% OH SD-FEC 阈值以下实现 40 km 内高达 80 Gbaud 的单极化 16-QAM DSB 信号传输，创下 258 Gbps 的净比特率和每偏振每波长 5.31 b/s/Hz 的净 ESE。]]>; </description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10113159]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3680</startpage><endpage> 3687</endpage><filesize> 2764 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Yixiang Hu;Xueyang Li;Deng Mao;Md Samiul Alam;Essam Berikaa;Jinsong Zhang;Santiago Bernal;Alireza Samani;Mohammad E. Mousa-Pasandi;Maurice O'Sullivan;David V. Plant;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Proposal and Demonstration of Free-Space Optical Communication Using Photonic Crystal Surface-Emitting Lasers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10120921]]><description><![CDATA[We propose and demonstrate free-space optical (FSO) communication using photonic crystal surface-emitting lasers (PCSELs). Unlike other types of conventional semiconductor lasers, such as edge-emitting lasers (EELs) and vertical-cavity surface-emitting lasers (VCSELs), PCSELs achieve much larger area single-mode coherent lasing, and this unique feature enables high-power (>;watt) and lens-free operations at the same time. To date, these advantages have been recognized to be game changing, especially in light detection and ranging (LiDAR) and laser processing applications. In this work, we show that FSO communication can also benefit from these advantages of PCSELs; more specifically, conventional transmitters that include low-power semiconductor lasers, optical lenses, and fiber-based amplifiers could be replaced with a single PCSEL. Since fiber amplifiers usually consist of bulky components and have low conversion efficiencies, PCSELs can offer more space- and power-saving solutions. Moreover, the narrow beam divergence angles directly obtained from large-area single-mode PCSELs can also eliminate the need for lens systems on the transmitter side. To experimentally verify these potential advantages, we performed FSO transmission experiments based on PCSELs and successfully transmitted 480-MHz and 864-MHz orthogonal frequency division multiplexed (OFDM) signals over 1.1 m using a 500-&#x03BC;m PCSEL in a lens-free transmitter configuration. We believe that PCSELs open new possibilities and choices in FSO communication.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10120921]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3688</startpage><endpage> 3694</endpage><filesize> 1723 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Shota Ishimura;Ryohei Morita;Takuya Inoue;Kosuke Nishimura;Hidenori Takahashi;Takehiro Tsuritani;Menaka De Zoysa;Kenji Ishizaki;Masatoshi Suzuki;Susumu Noda;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Demonstration of a 15-Mode Network Node Supported by a Field-Deployed 15-Mode Fiber]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124347]]><description><![CDATA[This paper extends a recent demonstration of a 2-line side 15-mode spatial division multiplexing network node. The node is based on fifteen 2 &#x00D7; 2 wavelength cross-connects (WXCs) to direct up to six 5 Tb/s, 15-mode, spatial super channels (SSCs). For this demonstration, we consider full add and drop, full express and partial add and drop network scenarios. The WXCs were made using three commercial 4 &#x00D7; 16 wavelength cross-connects, which were reprogrammed to each implement five identical 2 &#x00D7; 2 WXCs. The network node is demonstrated using a 6.1 km, 15-mode, multi-mode fiber (MMF) with a standard cladding diameter of 125 &#x03BC;m. This is the first field-deployed MMF and is installed in an underground tunnel in the city of L&#x0027;Aquila, Italy. We further extend the network node to support up to 20 SSCs for a throughput per line side of 100 Tb/s. It is shown that the MIMO requirements for this type of systems is strongly dependent on the differential delays of the different modes propagating within the network node.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124347]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3695</startpage><endpage> 3703</endpage><filesize> 1926年</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Ruben S. Luís;Georg Rademacher;Benjamin J. Puttnam;Giammarco Di Sciullo;Andrea Marotta;Robert Emmerich;Nicolas Braig-Christophersen;Ralf Stolte;Fabio Graziosi;Antonio Mecozzi;Colja Schubert;Giuseppe Ferri;Frank Achten;Pierre Sillard;Roland Ryf;Lauren Dallachiesa;Satoshi Shinada;Cristian Antonelli;Hideaki Furukawa;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Integrated Photonic Tensor Processing Unit for a Matrix Multiply: A Review]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10114395]]><description><![CDATA[The explosion of artificial intelligence and machine-learning algorithms, connected to the exponential growth of the exchanged data, is driving a search for novel application-specific hardware accelerators. Among the many, the photonics field appears to be in the perfect spotlight for this global data explosion, thanks to its almost infinite bandwidth capacity associated with limited energy consumption. In this review, we will overview the major advantages that photonics has over electronics for hardware accelerators, followed by a comparison between the major architectures implemented on Photonics Integrated Circuits (PIC) for both the linear and nonlinear parts of Neural Networks. By the end, we will highlight the main driving forces for the next generation of photonic accelerators, as well as the main limits that must be overcome.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10114395]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3704</startpage><endpage> 3716</endpage><filesize> 2320</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Nicola Peserico;Bhavin J. Shastri;Volker J. Sorger;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Achievable Capacity of Geostationary-Ground Optical Links]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10114466]]><description><![CDATA[We estimate the capacity of optical links at telecom wavelengths built upon existing terrestrial technologies. We study the impact of molecular absorption while varying the modulation scheme and compare the result with the ultimate capacity achievable in void. We then investigate the impact of atmospheric turbulence and evaluate how much capacity we recover with current mitigation techniques such as adaptive optics, and data coding coupled with delay diversity or data interleaving. We conclude by evaluating the achievable capacity in the presence of molecular absorption and atmospheric turbulence.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10114466]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3717</startpage><endpage> 3725</endpage><filesize> 1221 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Rajiv Boddeda;Daniel Romero Arrieta;Sylvain Almonacil;Jérémie Renaudier;Sébastien Bigo;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Geometric Constellation Shaping for Fiber-Optic Channels via End-to-End Learning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124361]]><description><![CDATA[End-to-end learning has become a popular method to optimize a constellation shape of a communication system. When the channel model is differentiable, end-to-end learning can be applied with conventional backpropagation algorithm for optimization of the shape. A variety of optimization algorithms have also been developed for end-to-end learning over a non-differentiable channel model. In this paper, we compare a gradient-free optimization method based on the cubature Kalman filter, model-free optimization and backpropagation for end-to-end learning on a fiber-optic channel modeled by the split-step Fourier method. The results indicate that the gradient-free optimization algorithms provide a decent replacement to backpropagation in terms of performance at the expense of computational complexity. Furthermore, the quantization problem of finite bit resolution of the digital-to-analog and analog-to-digital converters is addressed and its impact on geometrically shaped constellations is analysed. Here, the results show that when optimizing a constellation with respect to mutual information, a minimum number of quantization levels is required to achieve shaping gain. For generalized mutual information, the gain is maintained throughout all of the considered quantization levels. Also, the results imply that the autoencoder can adapt the constellation size to the given channel conditions.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124361]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3726</startpage><endpage> 3736</endpage><filesize> 1813 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Ognjen Jovanovic;Francesco Da Ros;Darko Zibar;Metodi P. Yankov;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Peta-Scale Embedded Photonics Architecture for Distributed Deep Learning Applications]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124987]]><description><![CDATA[As Deep Learning (DL) models grow larger and more complex, training jobs are increasingly distributed across multiple Computing Units (CU) such as GPUs and TPUs. Each CU processes a sub-part of the model and synchronizes results with others. Communication among these CUs has emerged as a key bottleneck in the training process. In this work, we present SiPAC, a Silicon Photonic Accelerated Compute cluster. SiPAC accelerates distributed DL training by means of two co-designed components: a photonic physical layer and a novel collective algorithm. The physical layer exploits embedded photonics to bring peta-scale I/O directly to the CUs of a DL optimized cluster and uses resonator-based optical wavelength selectivity to realize hardware multi-casting. The collective algorithm builds on the hardware multi-casting primitive. This combination expedites a variety of collective communications commonly employed in DL training and has the potential to drastically ease the communication bottlenecks. We demonstrate the feasibility of realizing the SiPAC architecture through 1) an optical testbed experiment where an array of comb laser wavelengths are shuffled by a cascaded ring switch, with each ring selecting and forwarding multiple wavelengths to increase the effective communication bandwidth and hence demonstrating the hardware multicasting primitive, and 2) a four-GPU testbed running a realistic DL workload that achieves 22&#x0025; system-level performance improvement relative to a similarly-sized leaf-spine topology. Large scale simulations show that SiPAC achieves a 1.4&#x00D7; to 5.9&#x00D7; communication time reduction compared to state-of-the-art compute clusters for representative collective communications.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10124987]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3737</startpage><endpage> 3749</endpage><filesize> 3670 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Zhenguo Wu;Liang Yuan Dai;Asher Novick;Madeleine Glick;Ziyi Zhu;Sébastien Rumley;George Michelogiannakis;John Shalf;Keren Bergman;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latest Developments in the Field of Optical Communications for Small Satellites and Beyond]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10128680]]><description><![CDATA[In this article, we introduce our vision for the future non-terrestrial networks beyond 5G and discuss the possible implementation scenarios for free-space optical communication technology in it, especially regarding the satellite communications segment. We show and discuss some of the latest system developments globally in the field of optical communications for small satellites. Together with the latest projects in the National Institute of Information and Communications Technology (NICT) of Japan for payloads for small moving platforms, a specific trend in the field is clearly defined. We further show our newly developed ground station for the experiments with our High-speed Communication with Advanced Laser Instrument (HICALI) payload and discuss the main challenges in a satellite to ground optical link and our specific solution providing preliminary test results of the performance.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10128680]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3750</startpage><endpage> 3757</endpage><filesize> 10259 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Dimitar Radkov Kolev;Alberto Carrasco-Casado;Phuc V. Trinh;Koichi Shiratama;Femi Ishola;Hideaki Kotake;Junichi Nakazono;Yoshihiko Saito;Hiroo Kunimori;Toshihiro Kubooka;Hiroyuki Tsuji;Morio Toyoshima;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Explore Benefits of Distributed Fiber Optic Sensing for Optical Network Service Providers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10091246]]><description><![CDATA[We review various applications of distributed fiber optic sensing (DFOS) and machine learning (ML) technologies that particularly benefit telecom operators' fiber networks and businesses. By leveraging relative phase shift of the reflectance of coherent Rayleigh, Brillouin and Raman scattering of light wave, the ambient environmental vibration, acoustic effects, temperature and fiber&#x002F;cable strain can be detected. Fiber optic sensing technology allows optical fiber to support sensing features in addition to its conventional role to transmit data in telecommunications. DFOS has recently helped telecom operators by adding multiple sensing features and proved feasibility of co-existence of sensing and communication systems on same fiber. We review the architecture of DFOS technique, and show examples where optical fiber sensing helps enhance network operation efficiency and create new services for customers on deployed fiber infrastructures, such as determination of cable locations, cable cut prevention, perimeter intrusion detection and networked sensing applications. In addition, edge AI platform allows data processing to be conducted on-the-fly with low latency. Based on discriminative spatial-temporal signatures of different events of interest, real-time processing of the sensing data from the DFOS system provides results of the detection, classification and localization immediately.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10091246]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3758</startpage><endpage> 3766</endpage><filesize> 17912 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Glenn A. Wellbrock;Tiejun J. Xia;Ming-Fang Huang;Shaobo Han;Yuheng Chen;Ting Wang;Yoshiaki Aono;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ultra-Long-Span U-Band Transmission Enabled by Incoherently Pumped Raman Amplification]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10099426]]><description><![CDATA[We demonstrate U-band Raman amplification in non-zero dispersion shifted fibre, exploiting the amplified spontaneous emission of an erbium-doped fibre amplifier as a broad-bandwidth, incoherent pump for low-noise amplification. By doing so, we achieve a high overall gain of &#x223C;22 dB over a 3-dB bandwidth of &#x223C;2.6 THz and obtain noise figures better than 4.3 dB and 5 dB in a 40 km-long, discrete amplifier configuration, in forward pumped and backward pumped scenarios, respectively. The performance of the U-band Raman amplification is also studied through transmission of a coherent signal over a 285-km point-to-point link. This work represents, at the time of writing, the longest-reach single-span U-band transmission demonstrated.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10099426]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3767</startpage><endpage> 3773</endpage><filesize> 3204 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Natsupa Taengnoi;Kyle R. H. Bottrill;Yang Hong;Lajos Hanzo;Periklis Petropoulos;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Technological Prospection and Requirements of 800G Transmission Systems for Ultra-Long-Haul All-Optical Terrestrial Backbone Networks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10102519]]><description><![CDATA[With the standardizations of 400GE and 400G completed or near completion, the attention is now refocused to next generation techniques with larger bit rates, i.e., 800G. We can see that current research commonly aims to short-reach or metro transmission for sharing key components with 400G, while ultra-long-haul transmission (typically &#x2265; 1500 km) based on 800G is still in unknown state. Moreover, all-optical networking with OXC and ROADM is being gradually deployed all around the world, which further increases transmission performance requirement. According to past progress, it is urgent for us to analyze and clarify the requirements of 800G transmission systems for ultra-long-haul all-optical backbone networks. This work provides the technological prospection and requirements of 800G transmission systems for ultra-long-haul all-optical backbone networks. Firstly, the field network status and basic technical requirements for 800G are analyzed. Our record real-time 10-&#x03BB; &#x00D7; 800-Gb&#x002F;s sub-carrier-multiplexing 95-GBd DP PCS-64QAM transmission over 2018-km G.654.E Fiber with pure backward distributed Raman amplification shows that reusing the components of current 400G technique is not the future direction. By numerically simulating the transmission performances of non-fully-loaded and fully-loaded DWDM scenarios, symbol rate higher than 180GBd, G.654.E, and optical bandwidth &#x2265;12 THz are necessary.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10102519]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3774</startpage><endpage> 3782</endpage><filesize> 4198 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Dechao Zhang;Mingqing Zuo;Huan Chen;Dawei Ge;Zhenhua Feng;Baoluo Yan;Dong Wang;Hu Shi;Shan Cao;Yunbo Li;Liuyan Han;Bing Ye;Yi He;Taili Wang;Han Li;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hardware-Efficient Duobinary Neural Network Equalizers for 800 Gb&#x002F;s IM&#x002F;DD PAM4 Transmission Over 10 km SSMF]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10105946]]><description><![CDATA[In this article, we discuss challenges and options for scaling IM&#x002F;DD transceivers towards 800 Gbps. Our focus is CWDM4 PAM4 transmission and our target distance is 10 km in O-band, which is a most urgent use case for next generation optical short reach systems like data centre interconnects and networks. At this reach and rate, chromatic dispersion (CD) becomes the main challenge. Its mitigation is essential and primarily done with digital signal processing. State of the art techniques, however, make transceivers quickly too complex. We show upon measurement results how neural network equalization can meet Volterra equalization performance with 30&#x0025; less hardware multiplier complexity. When also applying magnitude weight pruning, an additional 43&#x0025; reduction is possible without performance loss across all CWDM4 lanes. If needed, an added MLSE stage can further push performance in both cases. In any of these configurations, a key enabler against strong CD penalties is duobinary training, which is applicable to all feed-forward equalization architectures.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10105946]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3783</startpage><endpage> 3790</endpage><filesize> 1845年</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Christian Bluemm;Bo Liu;Bing Li;Talha Rahman;Md Sabbir-Bin Hossain;Maximilian Schaedler;Ulf Schlichtmann;Maxim Kuschnerov;Stefano Calabrò;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[All-Optical MIMO Demultiplexing Using Silicon-Photonic Dual-Polarization Optical Unitary Processor]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10128710]]><description><![CDATA[Dual-polarization (DP) arbitrary optical unitary processor (OUP) is a critical device to realize an energy-efficient multi-input-multi-output (MIMO) process of mode-division multiplexed (MDM) systems in the optical domain. In this article, a 6-port OUP with polarization-splitter-rotators is realized on a compact silicon photonic chip based on the multi-plane light conversion (MPLC) concept. All-optical MIMO demultiplexing of 300-Gbps 3-mode DP quadrature phase-shift-keying (QPSK) signal is demonstrated at 1540, 1550, and 1560-nm wavelengths with an energy consumption of around 1.5 pJ&#x002F;bit. Since all-optical MIMO is transparent to the signal format, the energy cost (J&#x002F;bit) would decrease inversely as we increase the baudrate, making it an attractive approach in reducing the power consumption of the future ultra-high-capacity MDM systems.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10128710]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3791</startpage><endpage> 3796</endpage><filesize> 2591 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Ryota Tanomura;Rui Tang;Go Soma;Shota Ishimura;Takuo Tanemura;Yoshiaki Nakano;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Implementing Neural Network-Based Equalizers in a Coherent Optical Transmission System Using Field-Programmable Gate Arrays]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10113728]]><description><![CDATA[In this work, we demonstrate the offline FPGA realization of both recurrent and feedforward neural network (NN)-based equalizers for nonlinearity compensation in coherent optical transmission systems. First, we present a realization pipeline showing the conversion of the models from Python libraries to the FPGA chip synthesis and implementation. Then, we review the main alternatives for the hardware implementation of nonlinear activation functions. The main results are divided into three parts: a performance comparison, an analysis of how activation functions are implemented, and a report on the complexity of the hardware. The performance in Q-factor is presented for the cases of bidirectional long-short-term memory coupled with convolutional NN (biLSTM + CNN) equalizer, CNN equalizer, and standard 1-StpS digital back-propagation (DBP) for the simulation and experiment propagation of a single channel dual-polarization (SC-DP) 16QAM at 34 GBd along 17 &#x00D7; 70 km of LEAF. The biLSTM+CNN equalizer provides a similar result to DBP and a 1.7 dB Q-factor gain compared with the chromatic dispersion compensation baseline in the experimental dataset. After that, we assess the Q-factor and the impact of hardware utilization when approximating the activation functions of NN using Taylor series, piecewise linear, and look-up table (LUT) approximations. We also show how to mitigate the approximation errors with extra training and provide some insights into possible gradient problems in the LUT approximation. Finally, to evaluate the complexity of hardware implementation to achieve 200G and 400G throughput, fixed-point NN-based equalizers with approximated activation functions are developed and implemented in an FPGA.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[June15, 15 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10113728]]></guid><volume> 41</volume><issue> 12</issue><startpage> 3797</startpage><endpage> 3815</endpage><filesize> 2709 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Pedro J. Freire;Sasipim Srivallapanondh;Michael Anderson;Bernhard Spinnler;Thomas Bex;Tobias A. Eriksson;Antonio Napoli;Wolfgang Schairer;Nelson Costa;Michaela Blott;Sergei K. Turitsyn;Jaroslaw E. Prilepsky;]]></authors></item></channel></rss>