<rss version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[ IEEE Photonics Technology Letters - new TOC ]]></title><link/> http://ieeexplore.ieee.org<description>出版物 TOC 提醒# 68</description><year> 2023年</year><month>七月</month><day>06 </day><item><title><![CDATA[Pyro-Phototronic Aided Self-Powered Photodetector With Hybrid Heterojunction of PQT-12 and CdSe CQDs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10158728]]><description><![CDATA[This letter examines the pyro-phototronic effect in a photodetector based on PQT-12 and CdSe colloidal quantum dots (CQDs), operating under self-bias. The device employs a hybrid heterojunction between PQT-12 and CdSe CQDs, along with a Pd-electrode. The use of pyroelectric materials, such as CdSe and PQT-12, enhances the device&#x2019;s efficiency by exploiting the pyro-phototronic effect observed during light transients. The investigation was conducted using both UV and white light sources, and the device demonstrated rapid response to UV light, with a rise and fall time of 14.18 and <inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX">${28.32} 毫秒$</tex-math></inline-formula> ， 分别。在 847 nm 附近，该器件实现了最大电流密度和响应度<inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX">${6.67} 乘以 {10}^{-{7}} A/cm^{{2}}$</tex-math></inline-formula> ， 和<inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX">${4.58} 毫安/瓦$</tex-math></inline-formula> ， 分别。此外，还使用传输矩阵方法评估了器件的光学特性，以确定其对特定波长应用的适用性。]]>; </description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10158728]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>911</startpage><endpage> 914</endpage><filesize> 11525 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Varun Goel;Hemant Kumar;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Impact of Plasma Treatment of n-Al<sub>远 UVC LED 中 V/Al/Ni/Au 触点上的 0.87 Ga <sub>0.13</sub> N:Si 表面]]>; </title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10158714]]><description><![CDATA[We investigated the effect of treating the surface of n-Al<sub> 0.87 Ga <sub>0.13</sub> N:Si 通过 O <sub>2</sub>或 SF <sub>6</sub>等离子体对随后沉积和退火的 V/Al/Ni/Au 触点的性能进行影响。 O <sub>2</sub>等离子体处理增加了接触电阻率，而SF <sub>6</sub>等离子体处理则降低了接触电阻率。因此，对于 50 mA 的电流，发射 233 nm 波长的远 UVC LED 的工作电压可降低 2.2 V。结果强调了氧对高 Al 摩尔分数的 n-AlGaN 表面上低电阻接触的形成具有不利影响。]]>; </description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10158714]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>915</startpage><endpage> 918</endpage><filesize> 5619 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Hyun Kyong Cho;Jens Rass;Anna Mogilatenko;Kevin Kunkel;Ralph-Stephan Unger;Marcel Schilling;Tim Wernicke;Sven Einfeldt;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Bidirectionally Focus-Tunable Optofluidic Microlens With Miniature Thermoelectric Coolers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10131896]]><description><![CDATA[The design and fabrication of a novel bidirectionally optofluidic tunable microlens actuated by thermoelectric coolers (TECs) are reported. A high-resolution three-dimensional printing technology is adopted to fabricate the truly three-dimensional structure of an optofluidic chip. Owing to the bidirectional thermal property of the TECs, both upward and downward membrane profiles are available under the control of a programmable direct-current power supply. The focal length of the liquid lens decreases from 25 to 5 mm as the voltage is increased from 0.2 to 1.1 V whereas the focal length changes from &#x2212;25 to &#x2212;5 mm as the current is applied in the opposite direction. A finite element simulation with COMSOL software is conducted to assess the temperature distribution on the device. The response functions of the TECs are investigated for the heating and cooling processes, and the imaging properties are characterized.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10131896]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>919</startpage><endpage> 922</endpage><filesize>第1427章</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Wei Zhang;Heng Li;Yong Chao Zou;Fang Xu;Ze Ren Li;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Single Step Fabricated Low Cost and Flexible Fano Resonant All-Metal Plasmonic Metasurface Absorber]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163233]]><description><![CDATA[In this letter, we experimentally demonstrate the absorption of near -infrared light by a one-dimensional (1D) Fano resonant all-metal plasmonic metasurface (APM). The low cost, flexible and reusable APM was obtained by transferring the 1D patterned plasmonic nanostructure made of Al from a compact disk on a transparent scotch tape. Control experiments on the variation of angle of incidence of light were performed to achieve the maximum light absorption, followed by polarization, reusability, and refractive index (RI) dependent sensing performance of the APM absorber (APMA). Electric field profiles at different incidence angles were simulated using finite element method (FEM) to explain the interaction of light with the APMA. Absorption of light is possible because of its confinement at the sharp edges of plasmonic nanostructure due to the SP modes generated at the metal air interface. APMA supports RI sensing characteristics with a maximum sensitivity of 1216.85 nm/RIU. APMA can be used to develop cost effective photonic devices such as sensors, spectral filters, heat absorbing protective photonic covers, etc.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163233]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>923</startpage><endpage> 926</endpage><filesize>第842章</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Sagar Kumar Verma;Sachin Kumar Srivastava;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Large-Scale Passive Optical Phase Array With 1024 Channels]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163399]]><description><![CDATA[Due to the advantages of fast scanning speed, good stability, flexible pointing, high resolution, small size and low cost, optical phased array has become a potential key component of beam scanners. The effective aperture of optical phased array determines properties such as divergence angles and ranging distance, and how to achieve it has been of interest to researchers. In this letter, we have designed and fabricated a 1024-channel passive optical phased array chip. A small divergence angle (0.05<inline-formula><tex-math notation="LaTeX"> $^{circ },,乘以 0.04^{circ }$</tex-math></inline-formula> ）是通过在Si波导上采用Si <sub>3</sub> N <sub>4</sub>微扰光栅结构实现的。基于该芯片，我们搭建了相干检测演示系统，并进行了相关实验。]]>; </description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163399]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>927</startpage><endpage> 930</endpage><filesize>第1439章</filesize><authors><![CDATA[Guangzhen Luo;Lei Yu;Pengfei Ma;Ruiting Wang;Langlin Cui;Zheng Wang;Hongyan Yu;Xuliang Zhou;Pengfei Wang;Yejin Zhang;Jiaoqing Pan;]]></authors></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chirped Pulsed Four-Wave-Mixing Spectrogram Retrieval From Multiple Shot-to-Shot Spectral Measurements]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163495]]><description><![CDATA[Four-Wave Mixing generated from a chirped pump pulse in a photonic crystal fiber can provide large gain bandwidth and high gain value offering great parameters for ultra-short pulse amplification. However, the time to frequency distribution of the bands is an important feature to improve the maximum amplification performance. Here, we present a method to retrieve the spectrogram from multiple shot-to-shot spectral measurements using the dispersive Fourier transform method without the need to inject a seed and any iterative complex algorithm.]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[Sept.1, 1 2023]]></pubdate><guid><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10163495]]></guid><volume> 35</volume><issue> 17 号</issue><startpage>931</startpage><endpage>第934章</endpage><filesize>2507 </filesize><authors><![CDATA[Coralie Fourcade-Dutin;Frédéric Fauquet;Patrick Mounaix;Damien Bigourd;]]></authors></item></channel></rss>